# Ahmed ElTalkhawy

ahmed\_eltalkhawy@yahoo.com | linkedin.com/in/eltalkhawy

# **Summary**

I am a certified(MCSA, MCSE, PMP) engineer with extensive experience in PMO hardware/software setup and technical support for Megaprojects using Oracle and Microsoft Products along with other software with In-depth knowledge and understanding of project management processes.

I have advanced skills in Enterprise systems, technical support & troubleshooting, Primavera, Excel, reporting / business intelligence(BI), data warehousing and database software among other software and tools.

# **Experience**

### Project Controls Engineer | Dar AlHandasah | February 2009 - Present

- Setup IT infrastructure and provide technical support for Project Management Offices(PMO) and remote project offices.
- Minimized services' downtime by developing risk management plans and executing proactive actions.
- Reduced various activities' time and cost by more than 50% by developing new tools and procedures to increase work throughput and reduce human error.

#### Responsibilities

- Install, Administrate, execute and monitor daily back-up process for Database servers(SQL Server 2005/2014 & Oracle 12c) and file sharing server.
- Installing and managing Oracle Primavera applications full stack from the Operating System up through Front End applications.
- Installing & maintaining NAS servers used for backups.
- Develop systems usage and security policies and conduct quality assurance analysis across project life cycle.
- · Provide technical support, troubleshooting and develop solutions for technical issues.
- Create dynamic dashboards and management/progress reports using Java, C#, VBA and SAP
  BusinessObjects Dashboards to address business problems and recommends corrective actions.
- · Aconex document control system administration and customization.
- · Prepare cost, timing estimates and design specifications for electrical, electronic and computer systems.
- Collect and identify requirements for enterprise systems(Project management, document control, database ...etc)
- · Prepare and execute risk management plan for related systems.
- Conduct value engineering studies for related systems.
- Define integration points between systems, and supervise integration process.
- · Conduct regular inspections, tests for systems, and supervise maintenance procedures when necessary.
- · Prepare forecasts and estimations resulting from significant deviations from scheduled baselines.

### Project Controls Specialist | GPME | August 2008 - January 2009

#### Responsibilities

- · Gather client requirements and define the most satisfied solution
- Assess open source systems and select best ones to be integrated into company's ERP system.
- Design and Develop Info Maker Based Report for Primavera Contract Manager

Ver 1.2 1 of 3

• Define integration points between "Primavera P6 Professional Project Management", "Primavera Contract Management" and other systems(Al and reporting, ERP, attendance ... etc)

### Software Developer | Future-Group | December 2007 - July 2008

Responsibilities

- Design and develop ERP modules for corporate ERP system(Transparent™) using php and MySQL.
- Design and develop custom reports for corporate ERP system(Transparent™).
- Design/Develop/Support day-to-day work activities like project management, document control, attendance control ... etc

### **Certifications & Courses**

- Microsoft® Certified Solutions Expert: Data Management and Analytics
- Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate(MCSA): BI Reporting
- Professional Electrical Engineer, Saudi Council Of Engineers(SCE)
- PMP (Project Management Professional) #: 1432285
- IELTS, Band 7
- Thomson Business & Professional Development
- Berlitz English Course Level 5
- ICDL V4.
- Master CIW Designer
- CIW v5 Foundations (1D0-510)
- CIW Application Developer (1D0-430)
- CIW v5 Site Designer (1D0-520)
- CIW E-Commerce Designer (1D0-525)
- CIW Web Developer (1D0-532)
- NSC First Aid and CPR course

# **Memberships**

- Engineers Australia
- Project Management Institute(PMI)
- American NCEES
- Saudi Council Of Engineers(SCE)
- Egyptian Engineers Syndicate

### **Professional Skills**

 Management experience, Deadline success, Team working, Loyalty, Positivity, Creativity, Adaptability, Tenacity, Leadership, Communication, Analytical thinking, Problem solving, Self-motivation, Good organization, Attention to detail, Quick learner

### **Computer skills**

 MS Windows, Linux, MS Office/Project, C#, Java, Bash, C/C++, PHP, Ajax, XML, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Assembly, Databases(MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle, MS access), Networking, Servers, Photoshop, Primavera Project Management, Primavera Contract Administrator, ERP, EPM, Aconex, Microsoft Power BI, Tableau, Python









Ver 1.2 2 of 3

# **Education**

## Bachelor of Electrical Engineering | 2006 | Aswan Faculty of Engineering

Major: Electrical Engineering Minor: Computer & Control Grade: Good – 72.09%

# **Interests**

Reading, Electronics, Control & embedded systems(Raspberry Pi & Arduino)

# Languages

Arabic(Native), English

Ver 1.2 3 of 3